# David I. Iglesias-Echevarria

San Francisco Bay Area, California 720-220-4635 iglesias.david.ignacio@gmail.com

### Intro

My professional goal is to design and build robotic systems that push the boundaries of what is currently conceivable and bring value to society in a sustainable way. Values-driven and experienced in fast-paced environments, with proven ability to work and learn both collaboratively and independently.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

**Robotics Software Engineer**, February 2019 – Present | *Verdant Robotics*, Hayward, US Autonomy and robotics applied to farming operations.

- Developed real-time camera calibration libraries and applications using Google Ceres
- Developed multi-sensor calibration algorithms using Matlab (IMU, GNSS, camera)
- Owner of entire calibration codebase, adding unit and regression tests and integrating those into the CI/CD platform
- Wrote camera drivers (Basler and Spinnaker)
- Wrote real-time 3D graphics applications using GLFW (OpenGL-compliant) and ImGui
- Code written was regularly tested and deployed on platform operating in the real world
- Joined at embryonic stage, helped company go through different funding rounds and demos

**Software Engineer**, January 2018 – January 2019 | *Point One Navigation*, San Francisco, US High-fidelity precise localization algorithms using cost-effective sensor suite.

- Contributed to different navigation solutions (loosely- and tightly-coupled EKF and SRIF)
- Wrote prototype and production code for both offline and online multi-sensor calibration algorithms using data from multiple sources (cameras, GPS/GNSS, IMU, wheel odometer)

## Graduate Research Assistant, August 2015 - July 2017 | University of Colorado Boulder, US

Developed novel algorithm for robot localization using an event-based Extended Kalman Filter as
part of the Cooperative Human-Robot Intelligence Lab. One paper published at Journal of
Aerospace Information Systems (https://arxiv.org/pdf/1802.07346.pdf)

## **EDUCATION**

**M.S. Aerospace Engineering**, Summer 2017 | *University of Colorado Boulder*, US Balsells International Fellow. GPA = 3.7/4.0

Thesis: Cooperative robot localization using event-triggered estimation. Advisor: Prof. Nisar Ahmed.

**B.S. Aerospace Engineering**, Summer 2015 | *Polytechnic University of Catalonia*, Barcelona, Spain Top 5% of the class. Scholarship to complete senior thesis at the University of Colorado Boulder. Thesis: Study of detonation waves in rotating detonation engines. Advisor: Prof. Peter Hamlington.

## **S**KILLS

- Estimation theory, probabilistic filtering (EKF, UKF, particle filter), sensor fusion, calibration, SLAM, multi-view geometry, localization, optimization
- Languages: C++, Matlab, Python, shell scripting
- Software/Libraries: Ceres, git, CMake, Docker, Jenkins, gtest, glog, OpenCV, OpenGL
- Fluent in English, Spanish, and Catalan, intermediate French

## **O**THER

Spanish citizenship, US permanent resident